direction of the farm buildings braying at the top of his voice.
It was the first time that they had ever seen Benjamin excited. Indeed, it was
the first time that anyone had ever seen him gallop.
"Quick! Quick! Come at once! They're taking Boxer away!"
Without waiting for orders from the pig, the animals broke off work and raced
back to the farm buildings.
Sure enough, there in the yard was a large closed van drawn by two horses
with lettering on its side and a sly-looking man in a low-crowned bowler
hat sitting on the driver's seat.
And Boxer's stall was empty.
The animals crowded round the van.
"Goodbye, Boxer!" they chorused.
"Goodbye!"
"Fools! Fools!"
shouted Benjamin, prancing round them and stamping the earth with his small hoofs.
"Fools! Do you not see what is written on the side of that van?
That gave the animals pause and there was a hush.
Muriel began to spell out the words, but Benjamin pushed her aside and in the
midst of a deadly silence he read, "Alfred Simmonds, horse slaughterer and
glue boiler, Willington. Dealer in hides and bone meal. Kennels supplied.
Do you not understand what that means?
They are taking Boxer to the knackers."
A cry of horror burst from all the animals.
At this moment the man on the box whipped up his horses and the van moved
out of the yard at a smart trot.
All the animals followed, crying out at the tops of their voices.
Clover forced her way to the front.
The van began to gather speed.
Clover tried to stir her stout limbs to a gallop and achieved a canter.
Boxer!
She cried.
Boxer! Boxer! Boxer!
And just at this moment, as though he had heard the uproar outside, Boxer's
face, with the white stripe down his nose, appeared at the small window at
the back of the van.
Boxer!
Boxer, get out! Get out quickly! They are taking you to your death!
All the animals took up the cry of, "Get out, Boxer! Get out!"
But the van was already gathering speed and drawing away from them.
It was uncertain whether Boxer had understood what Clover had said, but a
moment later, his face disappeared from the window, and there was the sound of a
tremendous drumming of hooves inside the van.
He was trying to kick his way out.
The time had been when a few kicks from Boxer's hooves would have smashed the van to matchwood.
But alas, his strength had left him.
And in a few moments, the sound of drumming hooves grew fainter and died away.
In desperation, the animals began appealing to the two horses which drew the van to stop.
Comrades! Comrades!
Don't take your own brother to his death!
But the stupid brutes, too ignorant to realize what was happening, merely set
back their ears and quickened their pace.
Boxer's face did not reappear at the